{"data":[{"question":"There was plenty of time. You ___.","a":"needn't have hurried","b":"mustn't have hurried","c":"couldn't have hurried","d":"must not hurry","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Needn't have PP: means that it was not necessary for someone to do something that they in fact did","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"Steven _________ you guys more help, even though he was very busy.","a":"might give","b":"should have given","c":"may give","d":"may have given","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Should have PP: used to say what would have been right or sensible, but was not done","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"I told Shirley how to get to my office, but perhaps I _________ for her.","a":"must have written it out","b":"had to write it out","c":"ought to write it out","d":"should have written it out","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Should have PP: used to say what would have been right or sensible, but was not done","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"We were really anxious. You ___ without telling us.","a":"needn't leave","b":"mustn't leave","c":"shouldn't have left","d":"couldn't have left","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Should have PP: used to say what would have been right or sensible, but was not done ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"The small tree is dead, I _________ it more water.","a":"would have given","b":"will give","c":"should have given","d":"must give","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Should have PP: used to say what would have been right or sensible, but was not done ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"I wish I ___ Nick last weekend.","a":"did meet","b":"met","c":"were to met","d":"had met","answer":"4","explain":"\n- A wish about the past: Wish clause,had PP\/ should, could have PP","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"When a pencil is partly in a cup of water, it looks as if it ___.","a":"has broken","b":"breaks","c":"had been broken","d":"were broken","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Clauses that start with as if\/as though express unreality, improbability or doubt if they are followed by an unreal tense \n- The simple past tense is used if we talk about an unreal situation in the present","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"We quarreled with the waiter about the bill. \"How silly! You _________ to the manager.\"","a":"should have talked","b":"would have talked","c":"must talk","d":"could talk","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Should have PP: used to say what would have been right or sensible, but was not done","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"Even if Peter ___ with you then, he _________ much for you.","a":"were, should not have done","b":"would be, would not do","c":"had been, would not have done","d":"had been, would not do","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Conditional Sentence Type 3: used to talk about things that didn't happened in the past and the consequence if they had happened \n+ Form: if + Past Perfect, would + have + Past Participle","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"},{"question":"_________, I would not accept his request.","a":"If I should be you","b":"If I were you","c":"If I had been you","d":"If I was you","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Conditional Sentence Type 2: used to talk about unlikely, imaginary or untrue events or situations \n- Form: if + Simple Past, would + Infinitive","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"1"}]}